自去年后进入公司后 我的妻子总是鼓励我
You know, after last year's corporate, my wife was always encouraging me.
她说，你干得很出色 你在公司干得很出色
You know, she said: you did fine, you did fine in the corporate.
我有些紧张 这小麦克风...哈罗，对不起
I was a bit nervous. This little guy... hello. Sorry.
这样很好，是吗？ 很好的背景，有人在那里
That's nice, eh? Nice background with the people there...
- 我们正在...我必须这样看？ - 直看着镜头就好
We are here at the... must I look..? -Just look straight at the lens.
我们现在在MNU（多国联）总部
We are here at the... MNU head office,
外星人事务部 我是维库斯・范德默尔
Wikus Van De Merwe Department of Alien Affairs. My name is Wikus Van De Merwe.
在我身后，你会看到其他 外星人事务处的工作人员
And behind me you can see the Alien Affairs' workers.
我们这个部门的工作是
And what we do here at this department is...
我们试图与大虾沟通交流
we try to engage with the Prawn
为了MNU和人类的利益
on behalf of MNU and on behalf of humans.
让所有人都感到意外的是 太空船并没有停在
To everyone's surprise, the ship didn't come to a stop
曼哈顿，华盛顿，抑或芝加哥
over Manhattan or Washington or Chicago,
反而直接停在了约翰内斯堡上空
but instead it costed to a halt directly over the city of Johannesburg.
船门在三个月内都没有打开 它就悬浮在那里，没人能够进去
The doors didn't open for 3 months. It just hovered there. Nobody could get in.
在深思熟虑之后，他们终于决定
And they eventually decided, after much deliberation,
最好的方法是切割飞船 破门而入
that the best thing to do would be to physically cut their way in.
我们即将进行第一次接触
We were on the verge of first contact.
整个世界都在注视着
The whole world was watching.
期待着，或许是…
Expecting, I don't know...
音乐伴着强光闪耀从天而降
...music from heaven and bright shining lights.
哦，天呀
Oh my God!
这生物非常营养不良
The creatures were extremely malnourished,
他们非常不健康 看起来精神恍惚
they were very unhealthy, they seemed to be aimless.
那时，我们承受着来自世界各地的压力
There was a lot of international pressure on us at the time.
整个世界都在看着约翰内斯堡
The entire world was looking at Johannesburg,
因此，我们必须做正确的事情
so we had to do the right thing.
随后政府成立了一个援救小组开始
The government then established an aid group that started to
将这些外星人运送到 船下方的建立的临时营地里
ferry the aliens to a temporary camp set up just beneath the ship.
我们并没有明确的计划 他们有数百万人
We didn't have a plan. There was a million of them.
因此，临时的收容所就成为了隔离区
So, what was a temporary holding zone soon became fenced,
并开始实施军事化管理 而在之前，这是一个贫民窟
became militarized. And before we knew it, it was a slum.
但事实是，没人真正知道 这究竟是什么地方
But the truth is, nobody really knew what this place was.
在第九区有很多不为人知的秘密
There's a lot of secrets in District 9.
片名：《第九区》
起初，大家的注意力都集中在
At first, a lot of attention was given to...
给予外星人一个适当的地位和保护
giving the aliens a proper status and protection.
为了维持那些外星人生活 他们花了大量的钱
They're spending so much money to keep them here.
而这些钱本可以花在其它地方
When they could be spending it on other things, but...
但至少这把外星人和我们分开了
...at least they're keeping them separate from us.
我想每个人都应该实际点 这些外星人将不可能回到他们原来的星球
l want to be realistic with everyone. The aliens will not be able to go home.
外星人会在这里长留下来
The aliens are here to stay.
对于这件事，人们有各种解释
There were literally thousands of different theories
至于船为什么无法操作 只能推测是
as to why the ship seemed inoperable, and what was speculated was that
指挥舱已经和主船分离了
the command module had detached itself from the main ship,
然后，又莫名其妙地失踪了
and then somehow mysteriously became lost.
它是自己堕落的还是按照预定程序？ 我不知道
Did it fall by itself or was it programmed? I don't know.
认真检查影像镜头
Examination of the old video footage
可以清楚地发现有一小块东西 从船上掉落下来
shows very clearly that a piece falls from the ship.
我们搜索它 我们到处搜索它
We look for it. We look everywhere.
这一小块堕落物引发了流血冲突
This piece that's falling caused us bloody problems.
发现了很多隐藏的武器
More energy weapon caches found.
特种部队突袭了第九区
The Special task force conducted raids in District 9.
有武器的地方就有犯罪 紧张状况不断上升，上升
Where there's a weapon, there's crime. Tensions rose, and rose.
人们变得越来越不满 并最终引发了骚乱
People became more and more fed up, and eventually the rioting started.
Tembisa的居民为了把外星人 从他们的小镇上赶走
Residents in Tembisa rioted for the third consecutive night
连续暴动了三个晚上
in an attempt to remove all the aliens from their township.
我想他们一定要修好那艘船 他们必须离开
I think they must fix that ship and they must go.
病毒，精心挑选一种病毒 把它释放到外星人附近
A virus, a selective virus. Release it near the aliens.
他们必须离开 不管去哪，尽管走开
They must just go. I don't know where, just go.
如果他们是来自其它 我们能理解的国家的话
If they was from another country we might understand.
但他们甚至都不是地球上的
But they are not even from this planet.
政府已实施全国宵禁
The government have enforced a nationwide curfew.
外星人，那些大虾 他们夺走了我的妻子
The aliens, prawns, they take my wife away.
这个贬损的词“大虾”用来指那些外星人 很明显，他暗指
The derogatory term Prawn is used for the alien, and obviously it implies
那些以食腐为生的低等动物
something that is a bottom feeder, that scavenges the leftovers.
我的意思是，你不能说 他们不像那种动物
I mean, you can't say they don't look like that.
他们看起来就是那个样子，不是吗？ 他们看起来的确像大虾
That's what they look like, right? They look like prawns.
外星人抢走了数额不明的现金，一个旁观者受伤了
The aliens made off with an undisclosed amount of cash. One bystander was hurt.
在外星人看来那些娱乐的事情
What for an alien might be seen as something recreational,
比如放火点燃汽车 让火车出轨
setting fire to a truck, derailing a train,
对人们而言 这些都明显是极端具有破坏性的行为
is for us obviously an extremely destructive act.
他们会抢走走你穿着的运动鞋
They can take the sneakers you are wearing off you.
他们会抢走你身上的一切 你的手机或者其它任何东西
They take whatever you have on you. Your cell phone or anything.
之后，他们会要了你的命
After that they kill you.
现在，20年后，公众的压力迫使政府
And now, after 20 years, public pressure had forced the government
将这些外星人移出约翰内斯堡
to shift the aliens out of Johannesburg.
他们受够了，他们希望 第九区搬走
They had had enough and they wanted District 9 to be moved,
并受到更多警力更强的控制
and more intensively policed and controlled.
因此，要实施这个大规模的驱逐行动 政府借助于MNU的力量
So, to enforce this mass eviction, the government turned to MNU.
欢迎你们，谢谢你们的到来
Welcome all and thank you for coming.
请认真听这个简短的声明
Please listen very closely to this briefing.
今天我们要开始一个非常复杂和棘手的行动
Today we start a very complex and delicate operation.
这是MNU所执行过的最大的行动
This is the largest operation that MNU has ever undertaken,
并且我们相信这次一定会执行地非常成功
and we believe that it is going to be undertaken successfully.
这次我们要将180万大虾
It is to move 1.8 million prawns
从他们现有的家第九区转移到 位于约翰内斯堡200公里之外的
from their present home in District 9 to a safer and better location
一个更好更安全的场所
200 kilometers outside of Johannesburg City.
我们在那里建造了一个更舒适的新环境 在哪里，大虾
We built a nice new facility where the prawn can go,
能够过得相对舒适 它们可以呆在那里
he can be comfortable, he can stay there...
大虾远离了约翰内斯堡和南非的居民
The people of Johannesburg and of South Africa are going to live
人们就可以过上快乐和安全的生活
happily and safely, knowing that that prawn is very far away.
UIO协议要求我们在驱逐前24小时
UIO protocol dictates that we give the aliens
给予外星人的驱逐通知
24 hours notice of our right to evict.
今天，你们将宣布这一正式通知 让外星人们签订I-27协议
Today, you will serve these notices getting the aliens to sign I-27 form.
MNU用来驱逐外星人的法律 实际上只是一个幌子
The legality that MNU is using to evict the aliens is simply a whitewash.
我将任命地区负责人来直接指挥
I'm going to appoint a field officer to take direct command.
维库斯・范德默尔.
Wikus Van De Merwe.
人人都说维库斯不是一个非常机灵的孩子
Everybody always said that Wikus was not a very smart boy,
但他是一个非凡的儿子 是我的维库斯，正如...
but he was a wonderful son. That was my Wikus, just...
感觉这是人生的一大步 谢谢你，皮耶特...史密斯先生
Feels like life on the big stage. Thank you Piet... Mr Smith.
我得抛开我女儿嫁给维库斯的事实
l had to put aside the fact that my daughter was married to Wikus.
那并没有影响我提升他的决定
That didn't affect my decision to promote him.
这个升职几乎和我结婚的日子一样重大 嗯...当然还没有结婚那么重大
It's almost as big as my wedding day. You know... not as big.
维库斯总给我亲手制作很多东西
Wikus was always making me things.
他说这这些东西都情深意长
He said that way they just mean so much more.
有一天，他把这个纸钵留在了沙发上
He left this paper-mache bowl on the sofa one day
而我并没有看到，我坐下了 并...把它压扁了
and I didn't see it and I sat down, and I... kinda squashed it.
为了调查，他们把他的所有东西都带走了
They took all his stuff away for the investigation, and...
而我向他们把东西全都要回来了
I made them bring it all back.
嘿，恭喜你，年轻人 谢谢，先生
Hey, congratulations, man! -Thanks, man.
你去P7 维库斯！事情怎样了？
Okay, you're gonna go to P7. -Wikus! -How is it going, man?
这么办吧，P9归你 谢谢
Here's the shake. P9 for you. -Thanks.
我并不是说他做的是对的，但
I'm not saying what he did was right, but...
他选择了那些给他的
he took the choices that were given to him.
- 这是特雷特 - 方德斯瓦, 特雷特.  -你好！
This is Trent. Fundiswa, Trent. -Hi.
方德斯瓦是我挑选来替补我的人
Fundiswa is the guy that I've selected to replace me.
- 今天他能做到吗，啊？ - 我会做到的
If he can make it today, eh? -I'll make it.
我现在只想每个观众
I just want everyone watching this right now
能从中学到一些东西 你可能会认为
to learn from what has happened. -You would think...
这些事情只会发生在别人身上 不会发生在自己身上
things like this would happen to somebody else, not to me.
情况怎样了？队友 你有我的东西么
How is it going, man? Long time, mate. Have you got my stuff?
喂，老板！  -最近怎样了？ 很好，老板
Hey, boss! -How is it going? -I'm all right, boss.
好，好，这是方德斯瓦 他今天和我们一起训练
Good, good, this is Fundiswa. He is training with us today.
我觉得我很讨厌他的工作方式
I think I was disgusted with the way he worked.
总是给别人暗示 和范德默尔
There was always just a hint of something not quite kosher
- 不是很合适 - 没人知道下一步他会干啥
with mr Van De Merwe. -Nobody saw it coming at all.
我们都不知道他将要做什么
None of us had any idea of what he was doing.
我想这是一个伟大的事情
l think it is a great thing to see that...
这次由非军方人员管理
it's not the military guys in charge this time.
不是说库布斯和他的那些牛仔不再重要了
Not to say that Koobus and his cowboys are not wanted.
你们这些家伙一直很重要
You guys are always wanted.
现在你看到了吧 这些都是他手下
You see now, these are the cowboys.
他们先射击，然后再回答问题
They shoot first, and then they answer the questions.
对不起，这是否超出了弹药配给的数量
Sorry, is this above the allocated amount of ammunition?
因为我看到你装了满满一袋子了
Because I see your pouches are full but...
我想也许你应该跟上校谈
I think maybe you should speak to the colonel.
F.A.G过来说我们拿了太多的弹药
F.A.G. over here says that we got too much ammunition.
不，我的意思是，库布斯，是那个
No, all I'm saying, Koobus, is that, you know...
你应该找到一个让他们工作更有效率的办法
you should find ways of making you guys more efficient...
听我说，你他妈的混小子！
Listen to me, you fuck!
赶紧让他滚远点
Get him outta my face.
无规矩不成方圆， 这世上我们都按照规矩行事
There are rules, we're all living by rules in this world.
我认为他那种做法是不可原谅的
Well, l don't think he can be forgiven for what he did,
- 因为这看起来就像是叛乱 - 我得开始出发了，Les
cause it's like a betrayal. -I've gotta get going, Les.
我想我们应该剪掉这个采访，因为我们将...
I think we're gonna have to cut this interview, cause we're gonna go...
离第九区12公里
12 KILOMETERS FROM DISTRICT 9
带上你的弹药，走 我们走吧
Take your magazines, people. Come on, lets go.
大虾并没有财产领土的概念
The Prawn doesn't really understand the concept of ownership of property.
因此，我们去到那里并说 听着，这是我们的土地
So, we have to come there and say: listen, this is our land.
请，你会走开吗？
Please, will you go?
自己一个人很难穿上防弹衣
It's difficult to put the vest on by yourself.
托马斯，你能帮帮我么？ 好的，头
Thomas, can you help me? -All right, boss.
他们告诉我要把防弹衣穿在里面
They told me I was gonna get the vest inside the Casper.
托马斯，看看那边还有防弹衣吗？
Thomas, just look on the side if there's a vest there?
我只是担心我的家人 别担心防弹衣，一切都会很顺利的
I'm just concerned about my family. -Don't worry about the vest, it'll be fine.
人权组织已经要求雇佣兵们在第九区
Rights groups have demanded that mercenaries should comply
应该遵从UYO规则
with all YO regulations in District 9.
我们正在第九区的入口出为你报道
We're coming to you from the entrance of District 9
今天，多国联合部队将开始重新安置
as today, Multi National United sets out to relocate
大约有180万外星居民
approximately 1.8 million alien residents from their homes.
人权组织正在保持密切观察
Human rights groups are keeping a watchful eye,
因为会有一些可疑的虐待行为发生
as many suspect abuses might occur.
我们正看到重装齐备的私人安全部队
We're seeing heavily armed private security forces
正被部署到第九区
being deployed into District 9.
并有大量的空中支援力量
Backed up by significant air support.
我们将进入一间一间小屋 并让他们在表格上签名
We'll go shack to shack and get them to sign the form.
第一个是EX247
First one EX 247.
我们看到车队停下来了 行动马上就要开始
We're seeing the convoy stop. The operation is about to begin.
集中精神
Just stay focused.
准备好了吗，托马斯？ 是的，准备好了
Are you ready, Thomas? -Yeah. -Okay.
那是一个信号吗？ 是的，伙伴们
Is that a signal? Okay, fellows.
你和我们一起 祝你好运，
You stay behind us. Good luck, boy.
别起来，他要去哪？ 这是什么？
Stay low! Where is he going? What is it?
很明显，安全性非常高
It's clear that security is very high.
这只是全面驱逐行动的前奏
This is only the beginning of a total clamp down.
我们是MNU探员 请开门！开门！
This is MNU agents. Open the door please! -Open up!
喂！喂！喂...
Hello! Hello, hello...
我是MNU的维库斯・范德默尔
This is Wikus Van De Merwe from MNU.
我们在这里来发放驱逐通知的
We are here to serve you an eviction notice.
你只需要将在这里签字就好了 滚开
You just put your scrawl there. -Fuck off!
好的！托马斯，慢着 我们已经取得了他的签字
All right! Thomas, hold it! We've got his scrawl there.
因为它碰到它了 这也算
Because as he hit it, it counts as a scrawl.
每次我们进去时，我们之间
First time we come in, there will always be a little bit
都会出现一些紧张的对立
of tension happening between us and them.
嘿，你不能吃那个
Hey, you can't eat that, man!
大虾喜欢吃橡胶 对他而言，这就像棉花糖一样好吃
The prawn likes to eat the rubber. To him it's like a marshmallow.
别，别！警卫！ 别这样对着着他
No, no! Guard! Don't confront him like that!
看到那了吗？ 平静点
Did you see that? Right in the roost. Stay calm!
这将成为一个问题 现在所有的大虾都出来了
This is gonna be a problem cause now all prawns are coming out,
他们想弄清楚发生了什么 停止！停止！
they wanna see what's going on. Stop it! Stop it!
把我的东西拿过来 看，他们都聚起来了
Bring my kit. See, everybody is gathering now.
别开枪，不然你将要把这里变成一个战场
Don't shoot or you're gonna turn it into a warzone!
- 那是什么？那是催泪弹吗？ - 不，这是猫粮
What is that? Is that a tear gas? -No, it's cat food.
这是猫粮 我只想引开他们的注意力
It is cat food. I just distract them.
其中一个袭击了大虾 他丢掉了他的手臂
One of them attacked the prawn and he's lost his arm.
不，这不是我的房子 我不住在那
No it's not my house. I don't live here.
那非常遗憾，你知道，这...
Well, that's a pity because, you know, this...
这是一种很好的猫粮 但当然，这并不是你的房子
This is a nice cat food, you know. But of course, it's not your house.
- 所以，我们要走了，把它给别人 - 是的！这是我的房子
So, we'll just have to go and give it to someone else. -Yes! It's my house!
我们要你在这里签名 现在你可以拿它了
We need you to sign here. Now you can take that...
好，停下
All right. Stop it!
这种生物变得对猫粮具有特殊的爱好
The creatures became incredibly obsessed with cat food.
一些像猫薄荷的东西，不过味道更重一点
Something about it, like catnip for cats. Only a lot more intense.
喂？MNU，我们正在发放驱逐通知
Hello? MNU. We are here to serve eviction notices.
什么是驱逐？
What is eviction?
我们在地球上这个殖民地陷入困境
What we have stranded on Earth in this colony,
根本上是因为人们不会独立思考
is basically the workers that are unable to think for themselves.
他们只会听从命令 他们不掌握主动权
They will take commands, they have no initiative.
他们丧失了一切领导能力
They've lost all the apt of leadership
不管是什么导致的 我们推断这是疾病所致
through whatever cause. We presume illness.
我曾在尼日利亚复合区执行过安全维护
I'm holding steady over Nigerian compound area.
有贫民窟的地方就有犯罪 第九区也不例外
Where there's a slum, there's crime. And District 9 was no exception.
尼日利亚人诡计多端 其中一种就是猫粮骗术
The nigerians had various scams going. One of them was the cat food scam.
在那里他们把猫粮价格以非常高的价格 出售给外星人
Where they sold cat food to the aliens for exorbitant prices.
你把钱放在这里 然后你就可以拿着这些东西离开了
You put the money here first. You don't get anything until you pay.
你想干什么？ 我将把你的嘴打扁
What are you trying to do? I'll chop your balls off.
更别提种间卖淫了
Not to mention interspecies prostitution,
而且他们也给外星人出售武器
and they also dealt in alien weaponry.
有车辆被劫持了 有商铺被打劫了
You have a car hijacking, there's a chop shop there,
你可以看那 那里有一辆车
you can see that, that's somebody's car in there.
第九区的尼日利亚人的头是一个叫奥卑山卓的人
The nigerians in District 9 are headed by a man called Obesandjo.
他是约翰内斯堡黑社会组织中一个非常有权势的人
He's a very powerful underground figure in Johannesburg.
你一定不想跟这些人打交道
You don't want to play with these boys.
他们会把你剁碎的
They will cut you into pieces.
那就是他们的头 好的，没问题
That's the boss there. OK, no problem.
别看他 会惹麻烦的
Don't look at him! This is gonna cause problems.
好，下一个是，766
All right, next. 766, all right.
MNU人员，请开门！
MNU agents. Open the door please!
喔！天呀！这是什么？
Whoa! Jesus! What is it?
检查另一面
Check the other side!
总部，我是维库斯・范德默尔
Control, this is Wikus Van De Merwe.
在JV766，我需要一只种群管制队伍
I need a population control team at JV 766 immediately, please.
检查另一边，托马斯 那里有40到50个蛋
Check the other side, Thomas! There is 40 to 50 eggs in here.
这正常吗？ 这真是一个让人惊异的发现
Is this normal? -This is an amazing find.
我只能向你展示一二 它是如何工作的
l can just show you a little bit how it works.
基本上，一头牛被悬挂在天花板上 就如你在这里所看到的这样
Basically, a cow is hung from the ceiling, you can see here.
它已经所剩无几了，当然 因为所有的这些管道
Very little of it left, of course, because all these pipes
都在给这些小虾蛋供送营养
supply the nutrition to the little prawn eggs.
你可以干掉一个，我来告诉你 想要看吗？ 不用了，谢谢
You can do one, I can show you, want to see? -No, I'm fine.
就这样，好了 这家伙再也没有营养供应了
There we go. Okay, no more nutrition to the guy.
最后，我们把氧气管也拔了
Then finally we take air back.
这些小家伙可以睡会了
The little guy is gone to a nice little sleep now.
你把这些东西拔出来 把它拔出来
You pop him out, there we go. Pop him out here.
你可以留住这个。你可以把它当作 你这一次行动的纪念品
You can take that. You wanna keep it as a souvenir of your first abortion.
- 你可以想象你亲手干掉了一个了 - 谢谢，头
You can feel like you did one of these here. -Thanks, boss.
好了，来了，伙计们 这是火枪
Okay, here it comes, guys. This is the snake.
如果我们一次只灭一个蛋
If we were going to abort each egg one at the time,
这会花上很长一段时间 所以，这样更合理些
it'd take a very long time. So, this makes a lot of sense.
听到了吗？现在正传来砰砰的声音
You hear that? That's a popping sound that you're hearing.
听起来就像爆米花
It's almost like a popcorn.
这些蛋就爆开了
What the egg does, it pops up.
这些留在那里的小家伙 就爆破开了
The little guy, what's left of him, pops out there.
所以，你们就听到了砰砰的响声
So that's the sound that you're hearing with the popping.
哥们，你不需要这个 只有女人才戴那玩意
You don't need that, man. Only sissies wear that.
在这里喝得有些醉了？
Been drinking a little bit here, eh?
你在对这电视做什么？这是什么？
What are you doing with this television set, sir? What's this?
喂，对着镜头笑笑
Hey, smile for the cameras here.
那是第一天的发现 那是一个大发现
That's a first day find. -That's a big find.
看到没？特雷特，看看这个 这里到处都是武器
You see this? Trent, look at this! There's weapons all over here.
CK 5, 7572...
一些枪很小
Some of the guns are small
但你一旦被射中 后果也是不可设想的
but if it shoot you, it make a big mess.
MNU出于人道的目地要迁走外星人
MNU is trying to move the aliens for humanitarian reasons.
但真正的重点 就如一开始所呈现的那样
But the real focus, just as it has been
焦点是武器
right from the beginning, is weapons.
MNU是世界上第二大武器制造商
MNU is the second largest weapons manufacturer in the world.
我们以为我们拿起外星人的激光枪
We assumed that we'd be able to pick up the alien laser gun
就能够射击 但事实上并非如此
and just be able to shoot, but it didn't work like that.
因为，我们发现 他们的技术实际上
Because, as we discovered, their technology is actually
整合了生物技术 要他们的DNA才能发动这些武器
engineered in a biological manner to interact exclusively with their DNA.
人类就无法使用 道理就是这样简单
It just doesn't work with humans. And it's as simple as that.
这画画的是一个大虾，三个人类
This is basically a guy, and there's 3 humans here.
应该是在警告我们
Basically trying to make a warning, you know.
似乎正在说“三个人都被我干了 你们离我远点”
He's saying "I kill 3 humans, watch out for me."
喂，别在自己的地盘上撒尿 退后，退后
Hey, don't urinate on your own bloody... get back, get back.
我是维库斯，请求第一营护送
This is Wikus, requesting First Battalion escort, please.
你想和他们谈 还是想和我谈
You want to talk to them or you want to talk to me?
不，不是他们
No, not them!
好的，伙计们，太谢谢了 是的，我知道，他有把铲刀
Okay, guys, thanks very much. Yeah I know, he had a spade.
看，我找到了
Look-I find some!
我告诉过你了...这是 人类的东西，毫无用处
I tell you before... this is human technology, it is useless.
只有我们的东西里面才包含着流体
Only our technology contains the fluid.
这不是我们的东西？ 不，这只是垃圾
This is not our technology? -No, it's junk.
继续寻找
Keep looking.
我发现了一些东西
I find something.
是的，这就是我们所需要的
Yes. This is what we need.
做得很棒，小家伙
Good, little one.
趴下
Get down!
小心...等会...
Careful... wait...
...那边
...there.
为什么一定要那么长的时间
Why must it take so long?
因为这相当困难...
Because it is very difficult...
...很多环节都可能出错
...so much can go wrong.
二十年的努力了
Twenty years of work.
我们的计划是不是已经准备好了？ 安静...听...
Our plan is ready now? -Quiet... listen...
...他们过来了
...they are coming.
你必须把这个藏起来 绝不能让他们找到它
You must hide this. They must not find it.
去开门并保持友好
Answer the door and be polite.
不！你带上它
No! You take it.
你看，这就是问题所在了 这就是团伙的标志
You see, this is the problem. This is the gang sign.
你看到这没？所以 看起来我们找到了
You see this? So again, looks like we have
越来越多的帮派成员
more and more gang members.
方德斯瓦，你先站在后面 你站在托马斯后面
Fundiswa, you just stay back. You stay behind Thomas.
这里到处是MNU的人 肯定会被发现的
This place is swarming with MNU. I will be searched.
我必须回到我孩子身边 别惹他们生气～礼貌点
I must get back to my son. Don't make them angry - be polite!
MNU探员，请开门
MNU agents, open the door please.
你好，我们想要你... 这里没人
Hello? We would like you to... -Nobody is here.
不能这样 那完全不可接受
Okay, that's unexceptable. That is totally unexceptable!
滚出来！滚出来！ 你这只蠢虾
Get out! Get out! You stupid prawn!
出来 来！走开，走开
-Get outside! -C'mon! Move! Move!
跪着 我进去看一看
On your knees! -I'm gonna have a look.
呆在这里 这里
Just stay there! Right there!
先生，我是来给你发放驱逐通知的
Sir, we have to serve you an eviction notice.
你不知道吗？ 不知道
Do you understand it? -No.
这是一个典型的帮派集会的场所 我可以看出来
This is a classic kind of gangsta shack, I can tell you.
我们肯定能在这里发现武器 小心你的头，别碰到牛
We're gonna find weapons here. Watch your head, don't hit the cows.
检查那些控制板 啊，你听到了吗
Just checking for panels. Ah, you hear that?
是的，里面是空的
Yeah, it's hollow there.
看，看那
See? Look at that!
我还没看过这样的装置 它看起来就像一个...
I haven't see this type of setup. It's almost like a...
化学实验装备
chemistry type of a set.
这里一定有些什么东西
It's gotta be something.
我不确定，这里有一些标志
l don't know, this has got the markings there of...
这毫无疑问是外星人留下的
...so it is definitely alien.
但这不是武器 但我不相信它
But it's not a weapon. But I don't trust it.
你没事吧？ 维库斯，你没事吧？
Are you all right? Wikus, are you all right?
关了它，请关了它
Switch it off, please. Just turn it off.
你会把这一段剪掉吧，那段它朝我喷射的
Are you gonna cut that part out, Trent, where it sprays me?
是的，别担心 记得把那段剪掉
-Yeah, don't worry. -You cut that.
我们刚在这里发现了一个危险的东西
We just found a dangerous object here.
里面有液体，而且我怀疑弄到人身上会引发伤害
It has a fuel in and I suspect it might leak onto people or cause damage.
所以我们把它装在里面，并带回实验室
So we just check that in and we take that down nicely to the lab.
这不是武器 但是很危险
It's not a weapon but it's dangerous.
我的直觉告诉我 他在这里隐藏了一些武器
He's got weapons somewhere here, my sense is telling me that.
我们检查另一边 托马斯！  ―是的，先生
Lets check the other side here. Thomas! -Yes sir?
托马斯，枪继续对着他 -好的，收到
Thomas, keep the gun on him. -OK, I got it sir!
枪继续对着他，托马斯 这里有个武器
Keep the gun on him, Thomas, there's weapons here!
哦，重大发现！ 重大发现，朋友们
Oh, this is Christmas! This is Christmas, my friends.
这我见过的最大的发现
This is the biggest find that I've ever seen.
总部，维库斯・范德默尔
Control, come in. Wikus Van De Merwe,
请求第一营支援
requesting First Reaction Battalion.
准备行动，伙计们
Stand by, guys!
这种枪我从没见过 你见过这个么？
This gun I've never seen. Have you seen this?
这真是太令人惊讶了！看看这枪 这是什么枪
This is amazing! Look at this gun. What gun is this?
这无疑非常令人惊讶
This is absolutely amazing!
你在做什么？ 我想把这个给托马斯看
-What are you doing? -I wanna show this to Thomas.
但我想你说你应付不了它
But I thought you said you can't handle it.
不，我不是应付它 我只是展示它
No, I am not handling it, I'm just gonna show it.
我不打算使用它 人类甚至不能使用
I'm not gonna use it, man. It doesn't even work with humans.
托马斯，看看这只枪
Thomas, look at this gun!
- 那不是我的 - 你是个军火商？ -不是
-That's not mine. -You're a dealer, eh? -No.
你听到了吗？ 你看到发生的一切吗？
You hear this, sir? You see what's happening?
第一营，我的朋友 你们知道这意味着什么
First Battalion, my friend. You know what that means?
这意味着你逍遥法外的日子结束了
That means that your days of flaunting the law are over.
看一看，你看到那了吗？ 那是什么？
Have a look, you see that? What's that?
那是一支武装部队
That's a firing team.
过来
Come here!
维库斯！你没事吧？
Wikus! Are you all right?
你以为你在干什么，阿？
Where do you think you're going, eh?
在刀枪面前，你跑不了
You don't run away from the chopper. -No, no...
你以为你能跑到哪？ 你想惹毛我？
Where do you think you're going? You wanna piss me off?
库布斯呼叫基地
Koobus to base, come in!
我们有两个人受伤了 MNU警卫，MNU探员
I've got two people down. MNU guard, MNU agent.
我是福克斯特勒特・杨基， 5-3-0，收到？
It's the Foxtrot Yankee 5-3-0... copy?
我们需要医护队，尽快
And we need a Med Evac ASAP.
不用，没事，库布斯 我并不需要医护人员
No, that's fine, Koobus. I don't need a Med Evac.
维库斯，你的手烧伤了 你得...
Wikus, you burned your arm, you need to...
我就在这里治疗就行了，库布斯
I'll just treat it here, Koobus.
先生，我真的认为你必须看看医生 进医生或者啥的
Sir, I really think you must go to a doctor, a hospital or something.
不，不 你得去医院检查一下
-No, no. -You should just get it checked out.
上点药就好了 扶我起来
I'll just have it treated by the medics. Help me up.
特雷特，你看到大虾跑得有多快了吗？
Did you see how fast that prawn was, Trent?
是的，他相当的快 告诉你，他相当的快
-Yeah, he was fast. -He was fast, I promise you.
看，我修好它了 它能工作了
Look, I fix it. I make it work.
告诉过你别碰它
I told you not to touch that.
有什么问题？
What is wrong?
没事，出去放风去
Nothing. Go outside and watch for humans.
你的朋友呢？
Where is your friend?
他死了
He's gone.
你没事吧？ 没事，就是感觉有点热
Are you okay? -Yeah, I'm just a bit hot.
你们觉得热吗？ 你觉得热吗，特雷特？  不热
Are you guys hot? Are you hot, Trent? -No.
是的，怕热就别进厨房
Yeah, if you can't stand the heat get out of the kitchen.
现在，你看看 到处都是小孩
Now you see. There's kids everywhere.
这就是我的意思 这就是我们要摆脱他们的原因
This is what I mean. That's why we get rid of them.
小家伙 是的，这就是我们为什么要让他们堕胎
-The little ones. -Yeah, that's why we abort.
让我们干脆一枪毙了他们 别，别，别，现在别开枪
Lets just shoot the little bastard. -No, no, don't shoot it now.
MNU探员，出来！
MNU agents! Come out!
你好，小家伙 MNU为你带来了糖果
Hello, little guy. MNU has sweets for you.
去吧，吃你的糖果
There you go, eat your sweety.
吃起来甜甜的 这个方法每一次都非常灵验
You know, eaty sweety. Works like a charm every time.
哦，去你妈的，死小孩
Oh fuck, man!
你差点用棒棒糖把我的眼睛戳出来了
You almost poked my eye out with the fokkin' lollypop.
死小孩，我尽量对你和气了
I tried to be fokkin' nice to you, man!
这是你们家的小畜生吗
Is this your fokkin' little brat here?
进去 对不起，对不起
Inside, go! I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
管教一下他 托马斯，让他出来
Teach him some manners. Thomas, get him out.
出来！跪下，我早已受够了你们的愚蠢的游戏
Come! Get down! I've had enough of your stupid games.
你们想要做什么
What do you want?
我们是MNU的工作人员 我知道
We're from MNU. -I know.
我们要你在这个驱逐通知单上盖个手印
We require your scrawl on this eviction notification.
- 我为什么要被驱逐？ - 是的，这是一个驱逐通知单
-Why am I being evicted? -Yes, it's an eviction notice.
把你的手印按在底下 看到没？你的名字在上面
Put your scrawl on the bottom. See? There's your name at the top.
- 是的！-克里斯多夫・约翰逊? - 所以在底部按上你的名字
-Yes! -Christopher Johnson? So, put your name in the bottom.
这里说你们必须24小时前通知我
It says you must give me 24 hours notice.
你们将到另一个地方 一个专为你们而新建的更好的城市
You're going to another place. A nice new city built especially for prawns.
- 一个很特别的地方 -而且我们还不向你们收费，明白吗？
-A special place! -And we are not even going to charge you, okay?
- 这不合法 - 签字！   - 不！
This isn't legal. -Sign the fokkin' paper! -No!
这个家伙很明显 他聪明点
This guy is obviously... he's a little sharper.
所以我们要另想办法
So we are gonna have to try something else.
好的，你好...听我说
All right. Hello... okay.
看来我们有些地方没有说明白，嗯
Seems like we didn't understand each other there properly, eh?
在这里你还有孩子
So, you've got a little one there.
- 那小孩有办出生证明吗？ - 有的
Do you have a licence for that little one? -Yes.
这里周围都是垃圾场 这对你孩子的生存很不利
There's a litter out here. This is dangerous conditions for your child.
75条文件说因为你的小孩生活在 一个危险的环境中
Article 75 says that because your child is living in dangerous
我们会把他带到儿童福利院去
conditions, I'm gonna take him down to Child Services.
我要跟你的孩子谈谈
I'm gonna go and have a little chat with your son.
离我孩子远点
You keep away from my child!
别用那肮脏的触手指着我
Don't point your fokkin' tentacles at me!
你说你想呆在这？
You said you want to stay?
你的孩子将要和我一起去福利院
Your boy is coming down with me to Child Services.
他的下半辈子就只能在1×1米的箱子里度过了
He's gonna spend the rest of his life in 1 by 1 meter box.
你好，小家伙，可爱的叔叔过来了
Hello, little guy! It's the sweety man coming!
操，看看这个，特雷特！ 操他妈的！
Fuck, look at this, Trent! Fuck it!
托马斯，拿枪指着他 他是彻头彻尾的罪犯
Thomas, keep the gun on him. He is definitely a criminal!
这里简直是个电脑商店
He's got a whole computer shop here, man!
我是说，这里太让人惊讶了，这里显然是一个
You know, this is amazing. I mean, this is obviously...
你现在可以看到这些失窃的电脑 被他用来作为房子的装饰
you can see stolen computers now that he's decorating his place with.
很明显，他没有许可做这事
Definitely he doesn't have the permit for this.
那小毛孩哪去了？
Where is that fokkin' little brat?
你在哪呀？我那个可爱的叔叔喔
Hello! It's the sweety man...
这里有糖果 嘿，我找到了...
It's the sweety... Hey, I've got this...
- 维库斯! - 特雷特,关了它
-Wikus! -Trent, turn it off!
- 你没事吧，头？ - 后退，后退！
Are you okay, boss? -Fuck off, man! Fuck off!
- 扔下他不管吗？ - 就把他留在这里吧
Shall I leave him? -Just fuckin' leave him, yeah.
明天我会过来见你的，克里斯多夫・约翰逊.
I'll see you tomorrow, Christopher Johnson.
当你和外星人打交道时 态度要和蔼，但立场要坚定
When dealing with aliens, try to be polite, but firm.
并且永远记住微笑比子弹便宜
And always remember that a smile is cheaper than a bullet.
- 感觉好些了吗？ - 什么？你觉得怎样了？
Are you feeling better? -What? -How are you feeling?
我很好，我没事 我只是有点头晕
I'm fine, I'm alright. I'm just a little bit dizzy.
能在那边停一下吗？
Can you just pull up there on the side?
我想在那吃点东西
I just want to get something to eat here.
你确定你要吃这些？
Are you sure you should be having that?
在你大吐那么长时间后
After your whole puking episode?
我感觉很好多了...我想 我需要补充能量
I feel a lot better... I think I just needed the fillings, you know.
头！头！
Boss! Boss!
有黑色的东西从你鼻子里流出来了
There's black stuff coming out of your nose.
天呀！
Jesus!
还有一个银造的圆筒 我找不到他了
It's a silver cylinder. I can't find it.
我一定得找到他 它里面有流体
We must find it. It contains the fluid.
它不在这里了
It's not here.
它应该在这里，继续找
It has to be. Keep looking.
我们要一万罐
We trade for ten thousand cans.
尼日利亚帮派
Certain factions of nigerian gangs
想把第九区的外星武器全部购买完
want to try and extract weaponry from District 9.
他们已经尝试了好多年
And have been trying to for many many years.
-给他100罐 - 100  - 100罐
Give them one hundred cans. -Hundred. -One hundred!
好的，好的 这次我们全要了
Yes, yes, but we take them all now.
好的，伙计们！ 给他们猫粮～抓紧了
Alright, boys! Get them the catfood - hurry up.
他们收集了大量的外星武器
And they amassed thousands of these weapons.
却无法使用它们
Without the ability to use them.
滚开！走！ 嘿，朋友，不是你，你呆在这
Fuck off! Go! Hey friend, not you. You stay here.
你想要什么 我想和你谈谈
-What do you want from me? -I just want to talk.
谈什么？
Talk about what?
愚蠢的虾 他们什么都相信
Stupid prawn. They'll believe anything.
“Muti”是个南非词
Muti is a South African word.
和魔法或巫术的意思类似
Today it's synonymous with witchdoctory and magic.
从这里把它切开 这是他们的心脏
You cut it here. This is their heart.
煮来吃能够治愈高血压
Cures high blood when you boil it,
治愈高血糖，糖尿病 能包治百病
cures sugar, diabetes, all diseases.
尼日利亚人食用外星人
The nigerians were consuming alien body parts.
他们相信这样做可以获取外星人的能力
They believed that by doing so, they were ingesting their power
从而就可以使用他们的武器
to use alien weaponry.
你必须吃掉它们
You must eat them.
这样他们的能力才能转移到你的体内
And their power will live in you.
给我个机会跑在你的前面，妈的
Just give me a fucking chance to go in front of you, man!
哦，宝贝！-嗨，宝贝，进来 我想去趟厕所
Oh, baby! -Hi baby, come in! -I need to get to the toilet, quickly!
为什么？怎么了？
Why? What's the matter?
宝贝，听着，我可能尿裤子了 -惊喜吗！
Baby, listen. I might have crapped in my pants. -Surprise!
这是干什么？ -庆祝你的升职呀 对，我升职了
What's this for? -Your promotion. -All right, my promotion!
爸，过得怎样？ 妈，很高兴见到你
Hello, dad. How is it going? Hi mom. -Good to see you.
太惊喜了 祝贺你  -谢谢
What a surprise, man! -Congratulations. -Thanks.
祝贺你，头儿 -谢谢
Congratulations, boss. -Thank you.
维库斯，出什么事了？ 宝贝，就是出了点小意外
-Wikus, what happened? -I had a small incident, baby.
我得去趟厕所 然后再回来跟大伙聊聊，好吗？
I'm just gonna go to the toilet, and then I'll talk to people, okay?
我得和你谈谈，和我一起来 -好的，不过我得...
I need to talk to you. Come with me. -Okay, but I just gotta...
伙计们，稍等我们一会？
Guys, can you give us a moment, please?
那边出什么事了？
What happened out there?
那些大虾们根本不肯听我的 其中一个还特别不守规矩
This prawn wouldn't listen to me, one really unruly prawn...
而我不得不 亲自抓住他
and I just had to... get him in my grasp.
听我说，那里今天死了很多外星人.
Listen to me, too many aliens died out there today.
我身后全是UIO的人
UYO is all over my backside.
听我说！你可别给我搞砸了
Focus! you're not going to fuck this up for me!
如果你无法胜任这工作 我就另找他人
If you can't do the job, I'll find someone who can!
- 嗨，你们好！ - 很高兴又见到你们
Hi there! -Nice to see you again.
这是不是意味着他要接管这次新的行动？
Does this mean he's in charge of this new operation?
- 是的 - 那太好了
-Yes. -That's nice.
维库斯！宝贝，你还好吗？
Wikus! Baby are you okay?
好了，让我们来切蛋糕
Okay, let's cut some cake.
史密斯医生，请到405房间来
Doctor Smith, please come to room 405, doctor Smith.
- 是不是感染的特别严重？ - 这有很多腐肉
Is it badly infected? -There's a lot of suppuration.
还有你应该知道我的右手一些手指甲变得很松动
Also you should know on my right hand some fingernails were coming loose.
还有黑色的液体从我鼻子里流出来 并呕吐过黑色物
And I had a black fluid coming out of my nose, and sort of a black vomit.
我的手怎么了 医生
What is happening to my arm, doctor?
这是什么东西？
What is this thing?
深呼吸 别紧张，平静点
Just breathe deeply. Calm down. Stay calm.
请叫我的妻子来
Sir, please tell my wife.
请注意，所有11区的病人，迅速隔离
Attention all medical containment evacuate ward 11.
停下，女士
Stop right there, madam.
怎么了？ 你们要对他做什么？
What's going on? What are you doing to him?
让我进去！
Let me through!
维库斯! 维库斯! 你们要把他带到哪去？
Wikus! Wikus! Where are you taking him?
好，抓住他了？ 准备好了？抓住了
Okay, got him? Are you ready? -Got him.
我们决定不用麻醉剂
We decided not to use the anesthetic,
因为我们不知道他会产生什么反应
the reason being we can't know how the subject will react.
Fester医生  -什么事? 我想你应该看看这个
Doctor Fester! -Yes? -I think you should see this.
我在他的夹克里发现了这个 这是外星人的吗？
I found it in his jacket. You think this is alien?
停下，冷死了！去你妈的！
Stop, it's freezing! Fuck!
暴露16个小时
16 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
这是哪？
Where is this?
什么？
What?
他们对这些大虾都做什么了？
What are they doing to these prawns?
痛阈测试，第一次，DBX7
Pain threshold, test one, DBX 7.
有很强的疼痛反应 说明神经系统已经形成
That's a strong pain reaction. That means the nerves have fused.
意思是，几乎融为了一体
I mean, it's almost completely integrated.
好吧，开始吧
Okay, do it.
B5，测试AMR-B5
B5. Testing AMR-B5.
清理障碍 现在就要，快点
Clear the range. Now, quickly!
转过来
Swing it around.
你们要做什么？ 们是锁着的
What are you doing? -The door is locked.
你能握住这个吗？ 这是什么？
Can you grip that? -What is this?
手扣进去 你们要我干啥
-Put it through. -Why are you doing this?
预备开火，预备 你们要我射击那个？
-Standby for fire. Standby. -You want me to shoot that?
退回...开火
Stand back... and fire!
很好
That's good!
奏效了
It worked!
好了，谢谢你
All right, thanks very much.
你知道我的妻子在哪吗？
Do you know where my wife is?
我妻子知道我在这里吗？
Do you know if my wife knows where I am, sir?
扣动扳机！扣动扳机
Pull! Pull!
不，我不扣
No sir, I will not pull.
你刚说老婆怎么来着？ 去他妈的，你老婆
What did you say about your wife? Fuck your wife!
- 扣动扳机！ - 我不扣！
Pull! -I will not pull.
开火！
Fire!
B7  -我可以扣动它 - 他说他能扣动它
B7. -I can pull it. -He says he can pull it.
我说我能扣动它 你他妈...
I said I could pull it! You fuckin'...!
B21
B21.
过去，快点 过去
Move, hurry up. Move!
- 现在，把它安置到铁链中间 - 放开我
Right, we want him in the center by the chain. -Get this off me.
快点！快点！
Come on! Time, time!
把他妈的大虾弄走 我朝猪开枪就是了，我开枪就是了
Leave that fucking prawn, man, I will shoot at pig. I'll shoot, sir!
听我说，我会为你朝猪肉开枪 我会开枪的
Listen, I'll shoot at pig again for you. I'll pull the trigger.
但我不会朝大虾开枪 听到了吗？拿走这些该死的枪
But I'm not shooting at prawn, you hear me? Untie the fucking gun.
人手扣动B21，非常不错 成功了
B21 in human hand. That's good. It worked.
拿走这枪 闪开
Just untie the gun, sir. -Stand by.
听我说，不能拿生命做实验 他又没有惹你
Listen, you can't use the real guy, he didn't do anything to you.
我要试试这个 所有的人闪开
I want to try this. Everybody standing by.
准备好没？ 3，2，1，开枪！
Ready to go? Three, two, one, go!
太不可思议了！
Amazing!
好了 试验到此为止了
All right! I think that's all we need.
先生们，我们时间不多了
Gentlemen, we are running out of time.
这是变形的关键阶段
This is the key stage in the metamorphosis.
他的DNA是人类和外星人的完美结合
His DNA is in perfect balance between alien and human.
但问题是，随着感染的扩大
And a problem is, as the infection spreads,
这个转变会变得永久的 并且越来越没有活力的
the transition becomes permanent and less active.
他将变成外星人的一员 变成一只大虾
He's going to turn into one of them. A prawn!
他变成什么不重要
What happens to him isn't important.
重要的是我们现在能从他身上获取什么
What's important is that we harvest from him what we can right now.
这个躯体价值好几百万
This body represents hundreds of millions,
甚至是价值几亿美元的生物技术
maybe billions of dollars worth of biotechnology.
政府、公司所有人都会为
There are people out there, governments, corporations,
这个东西拼个你死我活
who'd kill for this chance.
他能挺得过这些程序吗？ 不，当然不能了
Will he survive the procedure? -No, of course not.
我们要他所有的东西 组织，骨髓，血液
We need everything. Tissue, bone marrow, blood.
这个过程会把他拆得一无所有
The procedure is gonna basically strip him down to nothing. -Please...
亲属们怎么安置？
What about next of kin?
求求你帮帮我 别让他们这样做
Please help me. Don't let them do it.
我会处理那些
I'll handle that.
好吧，开始吧 好的，谢谢
Okay, I say let's go. -Good, thank you.
我不明白
I don't understand.
一切都说不通 他只是手臂受伤了，爸
None of this makes any sense. He just hurt his arm, dad.
医生们尽力了，亲爱的
The doctors are trying, sweetheart.
尽一切所能在挽救他们的生命
Doing their best to save him.
我们已经开始从样本上收获材料了
We're starting to harvest material from the specimen.
我们首先从软组织开始 先剖开胸膛
We'll start with the soft tissue first. Cut through the chest cavern.
我们必须尽快取出心脏
We need to get the heart out as quickly as possible.
一旦感染病毒了，病毒会飞快传播
Once it set the sinuosity, it just spread.
你一向知道维库斯 他并不那么强壮
You know Wikus. He never was very strong.
我来切开胸膛，取出心脏
I'll go through the chest, go straight into the heart.
安静些 操你妈！
Be quiet, please. -Fuck you!
我能见见他吗？
Can I see him?
还是不见好
Not a good idea.
走开！操你妈！
Fuck off! Fuck you!
操你妈！
Fuck you!
放下刀
Drop the knife!
走开否则我将割破他的喉咙
Move or I'll fuckin' cut his throat!
好的，好吧！
Okay. All right!
我会杀了他
I'll fuckin' kill him!
你得对他放手了
You need to let go of him now.
没事的，蒂尼娅 一切都会好起来的
It's okay, Tania. Everything will be okay.
史密斯
Smith.
什么时候？
When?
快叫库布斯
Get Koobus.
维库斯・范德默尔
...Wikus Van De Merwe.
白人，男性 30多岁 高度危险人物
White male, mid thirties. Is considered highly dangerous.
嘿，宝贝 维库斯，是你吗？
-Hey baby. -Wikus, is that you?
Smith夫人？ 你竟敢给我打电话！
-Mrs. Smith? -How dare you phone us!
你们这些人在我家里干嘛？ 不干你的事
What are all these people doing in my house? -It's none of your business.
我得和蒂尼娅谈谈 马上走开，这是我的房子
I need to speak to Tania straight away, please. It's my house.
你用的是我的电话，我是...什么？
This is my phone that you're using, mam. I'm fokkin'... what?
他想给我打电话
He tried calling me.
Anton，是我，快接电话
Anton, it's me! It's me! Accept the call!
我们都有13年的交情了
I've been friends with you for fokkin' 13 years, man!
滚开！你在看什么？ 滚远点
Fuck off! What are you watching? Fuck off!
我们都认为这是出于好意 因为他需要帮助
We all thought it was for the best because he needed help.
需要特殊医疗帮助
A special medical help.
而如果他继续逃亡的话就无法得到 医疗帮助
And he wasn't gonna get that as a fugitive.
他已经成为世界上 最具商业价值的人了
He became the most valuable business artifact on Earth.
他是唯一一个能够
He was the only human who had ever...
成功和外星基因结合 并还活着的人
successfully been combined with alien genetics and remained alive.
不过他真正的价值在于 他能够使用外星武器
But his real value was that he could operate alien weaponry.
你好
Hello.
能给我些奶酪汉堡和泡菜吗？
Can I get some cheese burgers and one large sauerkraut, please.
我们中断这个节目并给大家带来一个 惊人的消息
We interrupt this program to bring you breaking news.
有病人从隔离病房逃走 并且在这个城市逃亡
A patient has escaped from the isolation ward and is loose in the city.
维库斯・范德默尔已经被证实
Wikus Van De Merwe was recently apprehended
在第九区和外星人有长期的性行为
after prolonged sexual activity with aliens in District 9.
一派胡言 我得给我的经理人打电话
This is nonsense. -I have to call my manager.
这简直是一派胡言 你本该受命于我的
That is totally untrue. You are legally obliged to serve me!
已经导致他的身体发生变形
...is causing bodily disfigurement.
我只想要买我的汉堡 别听他们胡说
If I could just buy my burger, please. Don't listen to them!
这具有高度的传染性 警方警告民众
It's highly contagious and the police warns people
至少要与这个人保持20米的距离
to stay at least 20 meters away from this man.
别看这个手 这个手没事
Don't look at this hand! This hand is fine!
如果你有此人的任何消息
If you have any information regarding the whereabouts
请立即通知我们
of Mr Van De Merwe, contact us immediately on 0800-stop-wikus.
别动！
Stop!
暴露31小时后
31 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
你好，这是蒂尼娅 还有维库斯
Hi, this is Tania. -And Wikus.
我们暂时不能接听电话
We can't come to the phone right now.
请留言，拜拜
Please leave a message. Bye. -Bye bye.
总部，这里还没有维库斯的消息
Control, there's no sign of mr Van De Merwe.
全世界的人都在关注他
The entire world was watching him.
广播、电视台到处都在报道他
He was on every radio station, every image on television,
到处都是他的照片
anything you could find had his face on it.
他已经无路可逃 他只有一个地方可取
So he had nowhere else to go. He ended up hiding in the one place
他知道没人会去找他
he knew no one would ever come looking for him.
暴露40小时后
40 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
给现钱，不然别想
Pay now,or nothing.
下周给你，我保证
I pay you next week, I promise.
没钱，什么都不给 该死的大虾，这不是慈善
No money - you get nothing. Fucking prawn, this isn't charity.
你好，我想买一些肉
Hello, I'd like to buy some meat, please.
嘿，一个人！
Hey, a man!
是的，你这里有汉堡 或者牛排卷吗？
Yes, have you got a hamburger, or a steak roll?
难道这里看起来像是汉堡店？
Does it look like a hamburger shop?
你要什么肉？ 羊肉？
Which one do you want? Goat?
快点，快点 我可没闲工夫
Come on, come on, I don't have the whole day.
那是猫粮吗？ 是的，那是猫粮
Is that a cat food there? -Yeah, yeah, it is.
那来点猫粮
I'll have some of that, guys.
我操！
Fuck, man!
喂，喂
Hello, hello?
宝贝是你吗？蒂尼娅？
Baby is that you? Tania?
天呀，希望一定是你
God, please let it be you.
是的，是我
Yes, it's me.
我真是太高兴了 你给我打电话了，宝贝
I'm so happy you called me, baby.
维库斯，听我说 -好的
-Wikus, listen to me. -Okay.
我有些事情想对你说 而这真难开口
I have something to say to you, and it's not gonna be easy.
不，不，看...听着，宝贝 在你说任何事情前...
No, no, look... listen baby, before you say anything...
你父亲不站在我这边 而且他欺骗了你
Your father is working against me, but he's lying to you.
我从来没有跟这些
I did not have sex with one of these...
和那些外星人发生过性关系
...fokkin' creatures, man!
我绝不会和那种东西
I would never have any kind of
产生任何形式的冲动和性行为
pornographic activity with a fokkin' creature!
他们说你变成了他们的一员 我实在无法接受这点...
They say that you're becoming one of them. I can't do this...
宝贝，求你了，请别放弃我
Baby please, don't give up on me.
千万别放弃我 因为我可以...
Don't give up on me baby, because I can...
我想再次见到你，宝贝
I want to see you again, baby.
我的手会好起来的 而且我会再次见到你的
I'm gonna fix my arm and I'm gonna see you again,
到时我要亲吻你 要把你搂在怀中
and I'm gonna kiss you and I'm gonna hold you again.
我也希望你能再一次抱着我
I also want you to hold me again.
宝贝
Baby?
嗨，嗨，老兄！
Hey! Hey man!
好的...
...
我们现在直接搜索那个位置
We are on tracking directly to the location.
收到，我会给你一些支援备用的直升机
Roger that. I'll send you a couple of choppers for backup.
你！
You!
你想干嘛？
What do you want?
总部，发现一个目标移动到66
Come in, control, there is our target moving to 66.
- 你得走了 - 求你了，我需要你的帮忙
-You have to go. -Please, I need your help.
- 我们来玩捉迷藏 - 好的！好的！   不，退后
We're gonna play hide and seek. -Yes! Yes! -No, get back.
你应该让我藏起来？ 告诉我你最喜欢藏在哪？
You want me to hide? Show me your favorite hiding place.
走吧，求你了，离我们远点
Please, just go. Leave us alone.
不，求求你了，我得藏起来
No, please, I need to hide.
他们会杀了我的
They wanna kill me.
我只需要在这里藏起来 就5分钟，好吗？
I just need to hide in here, sir, for 5 minutes, okay?
这是什么？ 你们在这里干什么？
What is this? What are you doing here?
- 我记得你  - 什么都没 - 你一定能藏在什么地方
-I remember you. -Nothing. You must hide somewhere else.
先生...求求你了 你得帮帮我
Sir... please sir, you have to help me.
我流血不止 他们要杀了我
I'm losing blood, they're trying to kill me.
只有一种东西能让那个发生...
Only one thing that could make that happen...
快！我们得把他藏起来
Quick! We have to hide him.
你...，下去
Now you... get down there.
流体在哪？ 你们拿它干什么了？
Where's the fluid? What did you do with it?
求你了！ 你拿走了它...
-Please! -You took it...
我不知道你 在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
...我知道你拿走了它 我可以看出你身上发生的反应
...I know you did. I can see what's happening to you.
告诉我它在哪里？
Tell me where it is.
好的，好的
Alright, alright.
它是不是一个长容器里面的黑色液体？
Was it a black fluid in a flask container?
是的，就是它，是的！
Yes, that's it. Yes!
我把它没收了 实验室的人拿走了它
I confiscated it and the guys at the lab took it.
它肯定在MNU MNU的人拿着他
It will be at the MNU. MNU has it.
那是什么东西？
What is this?
- 你毁掉了一切 - 那东西现在在哪？
-You ruined everything. -Where is this?
这是你的房子？
Is that your shack?
这一切的东西都在你房子下面？
This whole thing is under your shack?
20年来，你一直在这里放 你那些重要的东西
For 20 years you've... had this fokking' thing in here?
天呀，这是严重违法的
Jesus, this is very illegal.
我在说，这简直是个大发现 真希望他们能逮你个正着
I mean, this is a find, you know. I wish they catch you with this.
能量从这里进去
Fuel goes in here.
够了！安静！
That's enough! Quiet!
然后我们就可以飞走了
Then we fly away.
我说安静 我们不能相信他
I said quiet! We cannot trust him.
他说的能量是什么？ 你们打算开动飞船吗？
What is he saying about the fuel? Are you trying to start this thing?
你们这些傻瓜要开动飞船然后飞走？
Are you little fuckers trying to start this and get away?
算了吧
Never mind.
你们这些鬼鬼祟祟的大虾
Yeah, you sneaky fokkin' prawns.
太糟了，我本来可以治好你的
Too bad. I could've fixed you.
什么？你说的治好是什么意思？
What? What did you say... about the fixing?
你说你能治好我是什么意思
What do you mean you could fix me?
算了吧，没用了，太晚了
Forget it. It doesn't matter, it's too late.
不，听着！听着 你是说你可以
No, listen! Listen. Are you saying that you can...
把我这只大虾手变成人手？
turn this prawn hand into a human hand?
你可以让变回人类？
You can make me human again?
我们主船上有医疗设备能够治好你的病
We have medical machines on the mothership that can fix you. Yes.
我们可以开这个小船飞到上面去
We can use this ship to fly up there.
那太好了！ 你们真是太聪明了！
That's fantastic! You guys are brilliant!
我一直都认为大虾们很聪明 那我们开工吧
I always thought that prawns were intelligent. Let's do it.
我没有流体
I don't have fluid.
我可以治好你，也能飞走 但我没有流体
I could fix you and I could fly away. But I don't have fluid.
对，好的
Right, okay.
好吧，我来告诉你怎样 我们为什么不...
All right, I tell you what. Why don't we...
再冒险一次，我们再去收集一些
go risk it some more? Let's go collect some up.
我们花了20年才收集到那一点
It took twenty years to collect that amount.
我操！操！
Fuck, man! Fuck!
操！唯一的那一点还被我没收了？
Fuck! The only one that exists is the one I confiscated?
是的
Yes.
这是地下四层
It's four stories underground.
- 他为什么一直那样看着我？ - 他喜欢你
Why does he keep looking at me like that? -He likes you.
我们是同类
We are the same.
我们不是同类 我们他妈的不是同类
We're not the same. We're not the fokkin' same.
只剩一个办法让我们脱离这个困境了 我们得从MNU手上拿回流体
There is a way out of this. We get the fluid back from MNU.
是呀，然后怎么办？ 然后我们两两都归西？
Yeah, and what then? Then we both die, eh?
我们都会死 这简直是个自杀行动
Both of us dead. That's a suicide mission, man.
你能不能别给我灌输这些愚蠢的主意
Can you not fill my head with that sort of nonsense?
变形正在加速
The transformation is accelerating.
你时间已经所剩无几
You don't have much time.
暴露56小时后
56 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
操！操！操
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
喂
Hello.
维库斯？ 蒂尼娅！宝贝
-Wikus? -Tania! Baby...
你没事吧？ 哦，天呀！谢天谢地...
-Are you okay? -Oh God! Thank God...
你在哪？
Where are you?
我在...
I'am...
我知道我父亲对我撒了谎 我知道他在试图保护我
It's not like my father said. I know he was lying to protect me.
我不知道该相信什么了
I just don't know what to believe anymore.
宝贝，我懂！但是请听我说
Baby I know, but listen to me.
这一切都是谎言，我向你发誓 他所说的一切都是谎言
It's all lies, I swear to you. Everything he said to you is lies.
我知道 什么？什么？
-I know. -What? What?
我相信你，维库斯 我只希望你回来
I believe you, Wikus. I just want you back.
我想要让一切都回到它应有的状态
I want everything back the way it was.
这...宝贝，这也是我想要的
That's... baby, that's what I want.
太好了 真的太好了
That's great! That's great news.
我可以让一切回到过去那样 如果你还要我的话
I can make it the way it was. If you take me back.
怎样？我们怎样才能回到过去？
How? How can we go back?
我有个计划 我知道怎么治好它
I have a plan. I know how to fix it.
我知道怎么治好自己的病
I know how to fix myself.
然后我又是我了 我们将会重新在一起
And it will be me. And we'll be back together.
你发誓？ 我想你发誓，宝贝
-You promise me? -I promise you, baby.
别放弃我，好吗？
Don't give up on me, okay?
因为我还没放弃你，好吗？
Because I haven't given up on you. All right?
我永远不会放弃你的
I won't.
我爱你 我也爱你
-I love you. -I love you too.
告诉我你已经定位到他了
Tell me you got a fix on him. -D9.
我们的星球有几个月亮呢？
How many moons does our planet have?
7个
Seven.
这个地球只有一个
This planet only has one.
我等不及见到我们的星球了 它比地球还大，是吗？
I can't wait to see our planet. It's bigger than this one, isn't it?
大多了
Enough.
我们现在可以回家了？
We go home now?
还不能回家，不能
Not home. No.
这个地方我们必须去一趟
This is where we must go.
看到那里的帐篷了吗？ 那是我们的
See that tent there? That might be ours.
我想回家
I want to go home!
我们回不了家了 再也回不去了
We can't go home. Not anymore.
喂，你不会想去那里的 那里一定不好
Hi, you don't wanna go to the tents, they are not better.
那里比这里还小
They're smaller than the shacks.
实际上，它更像是一个集中营
Actually, more like a concentration camp.
如果我能帮你拿回黑色流体 然后怎样？
If I can get you that black fluid, what happens then?
我们进入母船
We go up to the mothership.
然后你可以启动那玩意？ 是的
And you can start that thing? -Yes.
好的，那么让我们说清楚了 这手将会回到...
Okay, so just to be clear: this is gonna go back...
这手将会回到原来的样子
This is gonna go back to human like this.
我可以回家，你也可以回家
I can go home and then you can go home.
你可以带上你的小孩 你可以带上所有的大虾
You can take your boy, you can take all the prawns,
如果我能带来流体的话，对吗？
if I can get you that fluid, right?
你说过这是一个自寻死路的任务 你可能是对的
You said it was a suicide mission. Maybe you were right.
我们没有武器 他们一看到我们就会开枪
We have no weapons. They'll shoot us on sight.
看，看... 克里斯多夫
Look, look... Christopher...
我知道到哪里可以找到武器
I know where we can get weapons.
喂，伙计们，你们好
Hi guys. Hello.
我想买点武器
I would like to buy some weapons, please.
你究竟是怎么做到的？
How did you do this like that?
和外星人来后背式
A doggie style with the demon.
我喜欢它
I love it!
一个勇敢的白人男人 哦？ 当时戴安全套了吗？
One brave white man, eh? Were you wearing a condom?
我想要买武器，拜托了
I need to buy weapons, please.
你和我都知道里面都是些非法武器
You and I both know that there are illegal weapons inside here.
我带来了钱 我想那些武器
I have money and I would like to buy some of those...
坐下
Sit!
谢谢你了，先生，占用你时间了 非常感激你的接见
Thank you sir for your time. Thank you very much for seeing me.
我想买些武器
I would like to buy some weapons.
AK-47，一些手榴弹 催泪瓦斯也行
AK-47, some grenades... maybe tear gas canisters.
我知道你还有些武器在那里 我..
I see you have limpet mines here aswell, and I..
还看到过你们有外星人的武器 非常强大的武器
also see you guys have alien weapons there, which is great!
我能买一两件这种武器吗？
If I could have one or two of those.
我带来了钱，好吗？ 现在，我...
I have money, okay? Now, I'm...
先生，求你了，先生！
Sir! Please, sir!
我听说过你
I've heard about you.
你哪里变形了？ 给我看看
Where do you have it? Show me!
哦，妈的
Oh, shit!
过来，过来
Come here. Come.
别，别...请别这样
No, no... don't please!
你们这是干嘛？ 你要干嘛？
Why are you doing this? What do you want?
闭嘴！
Shut up!
再也不说武器了 再也不说武器了
Forget the weapons! Forget the weapons!
我要这只手，砍下来
I want the arm. Cut it off.
他说什么？
What is he saying?
我做给你看
I'll show you.
我的娘呀！
Holy shit!
告诉他们退下
You tell them to stand down!
告诉他们安静点 后退
You tell them to be quiet! To back off!
让他们把武器装到口袋里
Tell them to put the fokkin' weapons in the bag!
把武器给我，他妈的混蛋
Give me the fokkin' weapons, man!
别这样，看着我
Don't you, sir, look at me.
我说了，别盯着我看
I said don't fokkin' look at me!
你究竟是如何长出这只手的？
How did you get that hand?
快点
Fokkin' hurry up there!
当我跟你说话时，你他妈看着我 你有什么秘密
Look at me when I fuckin' speak to you. What is your secret?
你到底做了什么？告诉我
What did you do? Tell me!
我想要他妈的那只手臂 你到底干了什么
I want that fuckin' arm. What the fuck did you do?
你这个混蛋 我会去找你的
You fuckin' mazungo, I'm coming for you!
我会去找你的 我会逮着你的
I'm coming for you and I'm gonna get you!
放下刀 放下刀
Drop your fokkin' knife. Drop your fokkin' knife!
他对我们毫无用处 你就不能放松点
He's useless to us dead. -Would you relax?
为他妈的缘故，我手下应付这种事情 至少有100遍了
For fuck's sakes, my men have done this a hundred times before.
将猎物保持在视线范围内
Maintaining a visual on the location.
一切都会很快了结的
It's gonna be quick.
一切都会被清理地一干二净
It's gonna be clean.
最好的，一切都会无声无息
Best of all, it's gonna be quiet.
范德默尔还不知道会发生什么事情
Van De Merwe hasn't got a clue what's coming his way.
没人！ 他们哪去了？
It's empty! -Where are they?
目标消失了 此地空无一人
Target is gone. The place is empty.
你什么意思，没人？ 那他妈到哪去了？
What do you mean, empty? Where the fuck is he?
那个小混蛋根本不知道 接下来会发生什么
That little shithead has got no idea what is coming his way.
我会找到他的
I'm gonna find him.
那里有警卫，在门口 小心门口的警卫，伙计
There are the guards! At the gate! Watch the guards at the gate, man!
快点，出去
Move! Get out!
他们下去了 朝4楼去了
They're going down. Four stories down.
这是外星武器 给我现状报告
This is alien weaponry. Give me a status report.
是范德默尔 他在四楼
It's Van De Merwe. He's on level four.
切换到实弹 我们要把他搜出来
Switch to live, and then we're taking him out.
上校，我们不允许使用实弹
Colonel, we weren't allowed to use live ammunition.
他们想要捉活的
They want him alive.
留在这里，没我的允许，先别离开
Stay here until I call you. -I understand.
我得把们打开
I need to get the door open.
不！我说没我允许，先别离开
No! I said stay until I call you!
操
Fuck!
我还以为你说别杀他们呢？
I thought you said not to kill them?
他朝我开枪
He shot at me!
操！滚出去 别他妈得看着我
Fuck! Get out! Don't fuckin' look at me!
出去，都给我滚出去
Get out! Get the fuck out!
出去 都给我滚出去
Get out! Everybody get the fuck out!
出去，滚
Get out! Go!
移开这些东西！滚！
Move the fuck out! Go!
这是什么地方“ 别操心这个了
What is this place? -Don't worry about that.
他们在这里想干啥？
What do they do in here?
搜搜那些盒子
Check these boxes.
所有能装进管子的盒子都搜查一下 快去
Any type of a box that looks like it can hold a tube. Just check it out!
这些混蛋
These fuckers!
走，走，走
Go, go, go...
没人
Clear.
找到了，找到了
I got it! I got it!
Chris我找到了，走吧
Chris, I got it. Let's go!
克里斯多夫！
Christopher!
哦，操！
Oh, fuck!
听我说...我真不知道他们 在这里干什么
Listen... I promise you, I didn't know they were doing this.
直到他们上次也把我带进来
Until they brought me here the other day,
我向你发誓，我真的不知道 他们这样对你们的人
I swear to you I did not know they were doing this to you guys.
克里斯多夫... 看着我，听我说
But Christopher... look at me. Listen to me.
我们现在得赶紧走了，好吗？
We need to leave now. Okay?
整个MNU的人都会下来的
The whole of MNU is gonna come down here.
他们要我们的命的
He's going to destroy us.
我们能办到的，对吗？ 我们赶紧离开这里
We can do this, okay? We're gonna get out of here...
开火！
Fire!
快点，快点
Move, move!
朝大虾开火
Shoot at the prawn!
克里斯多夫!你他妈在干啥？
Christopher! What the fuck are you doing?
想想你的孩子
Think of your boy, for fuck sake!
你究竟在干啥？ 你疯了吗？
What the hell are you doing? Are you out of your fuckin' mind?
你会让我们都死掉了的 我们现在该怎么办？
You're gonna get us killed! -What do we do now?
我以为你知道出路呢？
I thought you had a way out?
我从来没有提到出路
I didn't say anything about the way out.
我答应过你我们一定能进去 我们的确进来了   -我想到了
-I promised you that we'll get in. We're in! -I have an idea.
你去哪？ 跟着我就是
-Where are you going? -Follow me!
你在做什么？ 做炸弹
What are you doing? -Making a bomb.
走吧
Let's go!
快点，进来！
Quick! Get in!
走！开车！
Go! Drive!
好的！
Okay!
好的，坐稳了
Okay, hold on!
操！
Fuck!
报道来自约翰内斯堡市中心的一个爆炸
Reports are coming in of explosion in downtown Johannesburg.
那里遭到了一次恐怖袭击
Well, there was a terrorist attack,
不过我向你们保证，我们正在处理这事 一切都很正常
but I can assure you that we dealt with it. Everything is fine.
飞低点 飞低点，下降
Droop it down! Droop it down! Decline!
他们里我们 很近了
They are really close to us now!
糟糕
Shit!
走，快走
Let's go, let's go!
别把那他妈的流体弄丢了
Don't drop that fokkin' thing!
快点，快，下来
Come on, move! Get down there!
下去并输入启动命令
Go down and initiate the binary commands.
赶紧降落
Set it down right now!
我们到达主船时，还要多久才能治好
When we get up to the mothership, how long is this gonna take?
把什么治好？ 治我的病呀
-To do what? -The fixing. To fix me.
可能要比我想的费时一些
It's going to take a bit longer than I thought.
好的，得需要多久
Okay, that's fine. How long do you need?
3年
Three years.
对不起，能说清楚点吗
Sorry, just go slowly with the clicks there,
你说的“3年”听起来想是地球上的3年
it sounded like you said "three years", like human years.
是的，三年
Yes. Three years.
什么？他妈的3年？
What? Three fuckin' years?
我会治好你的
I will fix you,
但首先我得拯救我的同伴
but first I must save my people.
我们的约定是：你能回家 我也能把病治好
The deal was: you go home, I get fixed!
我不会让我的同胞沦为医学实验品的
I will not let my people be medical experiments!
我就是他妈的一个医学实验品 听到我说的了吗？ 克里斯多夫？
I'm a fokkin' medical experiment! You hear me, Christopher?
我就是他妈的一个医学实验品
I'm a fokkin' medical experiment, man!
我必须回家并搬些救兵过来
I must go home and get help.
我必须用尽所有的流体 才能迅速飞回去
I must use all the fluid to travel quickly.
那我就得呆在这个烂地方了，克里斯多夫？ 我就得呆在这个鬼地方了
I'll just stay here, Christopher? I'll just stay here in this shack.
- 3年后我才能见到你？ - 我答应你，我会回来的
And I'll see you in three years time? -I will come back. I promise.
克里斯多夫！
Christopher!
他妈的去哪了？
Where the fuck is he?
嘿，你把维库斯藏在下面了？
Hey, you're hiding Wikus down there, my boy?
- 爸爸？ - 不，不要
-Father? -No, no, no.
你父亲得呆在这里把一些事情处理好
Your daddy needs to stay here to sort out a few things, alright?
我们得走了，不过我们会回来接他，好吗？
We're gonna go. We're gonna come back and fetch him, okay?
放在这里？放进去 放进去？
In here? -In there. -Goes in here?
你们是怎么打开这玩意的，大虾？
How the fuck do you open this, prawn?
爸爸
Father.
告诉我怎么弄，你这个混蛋 你是不是想让我弄死你？
Show me, you fucker. You want me to fuckin' kill you?
这就是你想要的么，阿？
Is that what you fuckin' want, eh?
好了...这里没有按钮
Right... there's no buttons.
开机
On!
激活？
Activate?
我老师只教过我
My teachers teach only:
一个大虾，一颗子弹
One prawn, one bullet.
难以置信，我拿钱就是干这事的
I can't believe I get paid to do this.
我爱看着你们大虾死去
I love watching you prawns die.
我操
Fuck, man!
爸爸
Father!
出去！出去
Get out! Get out!
这简直太奇异了
This is remarkable.
看起来有什么东西正从地下升起
It looks like something is emerging from the ground.
肯定有什么东西正从地面升起来
Something is definitely coming out of the ground.
好了...稳点
Okay... steady!
坐下，我没空搭理你了
Go sit down, I can't play with ya now.
维库斯叔叔正在开飞船
Uncle Wikus is flying.
一边去，一边去
Bug off. Bug off!
武器锁定目标
Lock the weapon at target!
锁定后开火
Fire when locked.
看起来飞船正朝领土的中央开去
It seems to be drifting towards the center of the territory.
我们已经锁定他了 开火
We have a lock on him. -Fire!
导弹已经发射出去了... 导弹打中了飞船
Something is fired upon... it has been hit!
这是怎么回事
What the fuck is that?
有一个引擎已经开始冒烟 飞船开始失去控制了
One of the engines is billowing smoke, it's out of control.
它堕落下来了，头 要不要我叫些兄弟去干死他们
It's going down, boss. Should I send the boys to fuck him up?
现在，飞船已经撞到了地上 重重一撞
Now... it hit the ground, the massive impact,
飞船已经停下来了
and it's come to a standstill.
我的儿子 我的儿子还在上面
My son! My son's in there!
闭嘴 把他带进去
Shut the fuck up! Get this fucker inside.
我们出发了 快，快走
We're moving out. Come, let's go, let's go...
快走
Move!
我们正在向目标靠近 以拍到更清晰的飞船画面
We're banking around now, trying to get a better view of the ship
飞船已经完全撞毁了 等着浓烟被清理掉
which is absolutely wrecked, waiting for some of the smoke to clear.
有个人被从飞船上带了下来
Somebody has been brought out of the vehicle.
看起来像是个人类
It looks like a human being.
我们得到一个未经证实的 消息说他可能是
We are getting unconfirmed reports that this might be
维库斯・范德默尔，是MNU的一个
Wikus Van De Merwe, a fugitive that has been on the run
潜逃了三天的犯人
from MNU for the past 3 days.
他们把他押上了车，并开走了
They are loading him into a vehicle now, and heading off.
暴露72小时后
72 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
怎么回事？
What the fuck?
我们抓到他了，头 把他带过来
We caught him, boss. -Bring him to me.
过来！回去
Come on! Get back!
我操！
Oh, fuck!
总部，我方与敌方交火，需要援助 需要援助，快点
Control, we're taking enemy fire! We need support. Backup, now!
出来，出来
Fuck off! Fuck off, man!
把手拿开 妈的，离我远点
Get you hands off me! Fuckin' get off me!
放开我
Get your fuckin' hands off me!
我难道没有告诉过你... 我会回来找你的？
Didn't I tell you... that I'm gonna get you?
你到这里，然后你拿着 本属于我的东西走了
You came in here and you left with something that belongs to me.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
去你祖宗十八代
Fuck you all!
我告诉过你这一天会到来的
I told you that the day will come.
你却带着我的战利品跑了
You've been running around with my prize.
我就想吃了你的手 变得和你一样
All I want is to eat that hand and become like you.
不！吃我的手不管用...
No! It won't work...
一旦我拥有了那种力量 就没人能够阻止我
Once I have that power, no one will stop me.
风水轮流转...现在到我了
It was your turn... now it's mine!
和MNU安全部队对着干 这些武装分子死定了
Fighting MNU security forces, this armed faction is doomed...
现在我要开吃了，我的朋友
Now I'm gonna eat, my friend.
我们刚得到消息说 外星设备已经被启动了
We're getting reports claiming that the alien device is activating...
你看到那个在车里的大虾了，是吗？
You see that prawn back in the Casper? -Yeah.
他对飞船的构造很了解
He knows what the fuck is up with that ship.
抓他出来，并使他开口 套出东西出来
Get that fucker out and get him talking, now.
三方部队正在靠近尼日利亚据点
Three contractors are closing in on the nigerian compound, and...
过来，外星人
Come, alien!
你有什么阴谋
What's your plan?
你们怎么弄到的？
How are you doing it?
谁在开那个飞船
Who's moving that ship?
好，这相当聪明
All right, that's very clever.
等我命令 确保一枪毙命
Wait for my command. Make sure you fuckin' shoot to kill.
操！快走！快走！
Fuck! Move it! Move it!
把那东西干掉
Bring that fucker down!
停火！停火！ 原地别动
Hold you fire! Hold your fire and keep your positions!
他是范德默尔
It's Van De Merwe.
嘿，混蛋
Hey, Dickus!
我回来救那外星人的 是吗？
I'll come back for prawn, alright guys?
听到没？ 快跑呀，维库斯
Do you hear me, now? -Run, Wikus!
听到我说的没？ 快跑呀
-You hear me? -Run!
继续跑呀 你这个胆小鬼
And keep on running, you fuckin' coward!
快跑，快跑
Run! Run!
请求空中支援 跟踪他
Get the air support up, and get on his fuckin' trail, now!
不起作用，头 他嘴硬得很
It's not gonna work, boss. He's a tough one.
他根本不透露任何消息 那直接毙了他
He's not gonna talk. -Then just fuckin' kill him.
操
Fuck!
他嘴很硬 不肯透露消息
He's a tough one. He's not gonna talk.
那就直接毙了他
Then just fuckin' kill him.
嘿，过来，起来 我要带你离开这
Hey, c'mon. Get up! I'm gonna get you out of here.
我不行了...太远了 不远，快起来
-I can't... it's too far. -It's not too fokkin' far. Get up!
我会带你过去 我要把你带到你儿子身边
I'm gonna get you there. I'm gonna get you to your boy!
来吧，跟我我身后
C'mon, stay behind me!
后退
Go back!
快跑，快跑，快跑
Run, run, run!
现在到达目地的了 我们得清除障碍
Arriving at the location now. We have a clearance to engage.
外星人过来了 趴下，趴下
Prawns are coming, get down, get down!
他们在朝降落点过去了 杀了这些混蛋
There are headed for a drop site. Knock these fuckers off!
来吧，来吧...
Come to mommy, come...
操
Fuck!
糟糕
Shit!
你受伤了？
Are you hurt?
我们可以做到 我手臂中弹了
We can make it. I was shot in the arm.
我们可以做到 快点
We can make it, come on!
听着，你直走 你可以做到的
Listen, you go ahead. You can make it.
我来拖住他们 我待会再和你会合
I'm gonna just... hold them off here, and I'll join you soon.
不，我们要并肩作战 我不会丢下你的
No, we stick together. I'm not leaving you here.
带着你的孩子回家 你得做到
Take your boy and go home. You have to make it.
别让我的辛苦白费了
Don't make me go through all of this and not make it.
你明白吗？ 我会回来找你的
Do you understand? -I will come back for you.
赶紧！在我改变主意前 快走
Go! Go now before I change my mind! Go!
3年，我答应过你
Three years. I promise.
我他妈一点都不怕你们
I'm not fuckin' scared of you!
朝我开枪呀
Quit fuckin' with me!
想抓住我？ 想抓住我？
You want me? You want me?
这就是你那点本事吗？
Is that all you got?
你他妈就那点本事吗？
Is that all you fuckin' got?
从主飞船上发来一束 强烈的光线
Some kind of quite extraordinary light from the mothership.
我从来没有见过任何类似的东西 它像一道光束
I've never seen anything like it. It's a beam of light...
全面扫描，好的
Full scan. Okay.
开火
Fire!
- 把那车开过来，快点 - 好的，上校   -快点快点
-Get to the vehicle, now! Get going. -Yes colonel. -Go, go, go!
操
Fuck!
不敢和我玩了，Koobus！
Quit playing with me, Koobus!
你这个混蛋
You fucker!
快走，克里斯，走
Go, Chris, go.
回家
Go home.
我们现在回家了？
We go home now?
是的
Yes.
暴露74小时后
74 HOURS AFTER EXPOSURE
简直难以置信
Unbelievable.
现在我知道为什么人人都 想分一杯羹了
Now I know why everybody wants a piece of you.
我都迫不及待想让医生 解剖你了
I can't wait for those med boys to cut you up.
但你知道嘛？
But you know what?
我不会再让你浪费我的一分一秒了
You're not gonna waste any more of my time.
你这个半兽人
You half-breed piece of shit!
我要亲手宰了你
I'm gonna just fuckin' kill you myself.
退后，你他妈的 退后
Stay back, you fuck! Stay back!
退后
Stay back!
约翰内斯堡的所有人
The people everywhere across Johannesburg
都冲出了办公室，涌向街头
are flooding the streets and pouring out of their offices
所有的眼睛都在注视着这个重大的场面
and all eyes are pointed up towards the sky on this momentous day.
这是20年来，飞船首次
It's the first time, ladies and gentlemen, in over two decades,
向大家展示移动的痕迹
that the mothership has shown any sign of movement,
人群极度沸腾
and people are tremendously excited.
整座城市都凝固了
The city had come to an absolute standstill.
大家都想知道接下来会发生什么
Everybody wants to know what's going to happen next.
究竟 克里斯多夫・约翰逊会不会回来 已经无从考证了
There's no way of knowing whether or not Christopher Johnson will return.
不知道他是不是逃亡了
We don't know if he was simply escaping,
或者他在实施一个营救计划
whether he will effect a rescue plan...
或者，会不会像媒体所言
...and, as the so called free press says,
会不会回来，向我们宣战
whether or not he will come back and declare a war on us.
这是维库斯・范德默尔 最后的影像记录
This is the last known footage of Wikus Van De Merwe.
他究竟发生了什么 我们只能猜测了
And we can only speculate as to what has happened to him.
一种阴谋论的理论是这样解释的
The more zany conspiracy theories state that
他已经被MNU或他国政府
he's been captured by MNU or by another government.
或者是政府特工逮捕了
Or by perhaps some shady government agency
已经被囚禁了起来
and he's actually being held in captivity.
如果我们知道他在哪里？ 我们会试图帮助他
If we knew where he was, we would try and help him,
而这才是难点所在，我们不知道 他身处何方
and that is the most difficult part, not knowing where he is.
维库斯，很不幸的是，已经离开了 把所有的问题
Wikus, sadly, is gone but I'm the one who stays behind
留给了我一个人 而我却无法回答
with all the questions. I can't give the answers.
在我心里，他早已去了 仅此而已
He died in my mind a long time ago. And that's that.
维库斯・范德默尔这个名字已经 是家喻户晓了
Wikus Van Der Merwe is a name that will become very widely known
因为他在整个事件中 扮演了关键的角色
because of this pivotal role that he played in this whole event.
他是一个诚实的人 他不应该承受这一切
He was an honest man, and he didn't deserve any of what happened to him.
我是说，我进入了一个电脑系统 并发现了一些事实
I mean, I know. I looked into a computer system and I found stuff.
我的意思是所有的数据 都在里面
I mean, the whole data was there, you know?
他们连藏都 没藏好这些数据
They didn't even do a good job of hiding it.
方德斯瓦・莫拉嘎正在候审
Fundiswa Mhlanga is currently awaiting trial
由于曝光了MNU的非法基因研究项目
for exposing MNU's illegal genetic research program.
在外星人重安居计划完成后
District 9 was demolished
第九区已经被拆毁了
after the alien resettlement operation was completed.
第十区现在容纳有250万外星人 而且数目仍在增长...
District 10 now houses 2.5 million aliens and continues to grow...
你们还没见过我老婆的照片吧 给你们看看吧
You guys haven't seen a picture of my wife. Let me show you my wife.
她是我的天使
She's my special angel.
穿上婚纱，她看起来简直就像是天使 你们想看看吗？
She even looks like an angel with veil, you want to see that?
看，白色的婚纱...
Look, you see, with the white veil over the...
她看起来就像是天使 所有人都说我的老婆是天使
she even looks like an angel. Everyone says that his wife is angel,
这就是你透过镜头看到的 真正的天使
but this is a real angel that you see there, on the cameras.
他们不会把这个也播出去吧 应该不会
They won't put that in the video, I don't think.
我在门前发现了这个
I found this at my front door.
一定是某个人留下的
As tho somebody had just left it there.
我的朋友们说 我应该把这个扔掉
My friends say that I should throw it away,
因为它只是一片废物
cause it's just a piece of rubbish.
可能是他送给我的 这好像很荒谬
That it couldn't possibly come from him.
但我相信这是真的
I know it's true.